If Israel has the right to defend itself, what the fuck were they doing in Latin America?
So this is basically episode two of me reading the Palestine Laboratory, which basically talks
about all the fucked up shit Israel did around the world. What if I told you that in the long
history of Haiti or Haiti, there was someone giving to people that were in power, horrible
people in order to Haitians. It was Israel. I'm going to read you the passage that Palestine
Laboratory talks about Haiti and everything that Israel did in Haiti. Another example,
Haiti under Francois Papadoc Duvalier and his son Jean-Claude Baby Doc Duvalier, whose family
ruled between 1957 and 1986, received Israel's Uzi machine guns, armored vehicles, and devices
for placing weapon systems on aircraft. The Duvalier dynasty unaligned between 30,000 and 60,000
people, but despite this, to curry favor with Papadoc, Israel's Ministry of Foreign Affairs
had a book by him translated. On one of the first pages, under a picture of Papadoc was
the caption, Haitian president for the rest of his life. As a reward, Haiti strongly supported
Israel after the 1967 Six-Day War. Israel's lawyer, Heidi Mack, an Israeli human rights
activist, filed a Freedom of Information request in Israel in 2019 to gain documents from the
Ministry of Defense about its relationship with Haiti under Duvalier, but their request
was denied by the court. Tel Aviv District Court Judge Hagai Brenner, in rejecting the request
in February 2021, claimed that releasing the documents could greatly embarrass the state.
Now hear this. The original documents contained racist and derogatory language by Israeli officials
towards Haitians, mocking their poverty and skin color, and so Judge Brenner claimed that
this was the reason not to allow them into the public realm. Files, she wrote, which include
the use of insulting terminology that was accepted about 50 years ago and which today is perceived
in a particularly negative light, may damage the country's image and foreign relations. Brenner
also worried that allowing the documents to be made public might assist the boycott, divestment,
and sanctions BDS movement against Israel, the boycott movement that is currently happening right
now. So according to this Tel Aviv judge, because they said it 50 years ago, it wasn't offensive
back then, but they had trouble releasing it now because it's offensive nowadays. What? And do you see
how towards the end, they were talking about how they were worried that if people found this out
about Haiti, people would start to support the BDS movement? Yeah. Mind you, I saw this sign at a
protest that I was at. Haitians are not stupid. They know what the West has done to their country.
So yeah, the next time you want to say, oh, Israel's just defending themselves, ask yourselves,
what the fuck were they doing in Haiti? And it doesn't stop at Argentina and Haiti.
They did this in Paraguay, Honduras, Nicaragua, Guatemala, Mexico, you name it.